Anamoul Rouf

I'm a Product Designer with more than 7 years of working experience in building bridges between business, technology and human.

I believe in design practice that is data-informed and driven by empathy. I'm passionate about finding the balance between complex business requirements and user needs, through a user-centered design process.

Work History

Product Designer at Curogram From APR 2022 to Continue.

Curogram is a communications tool for medical offices.

- · Effectively communicate research findings, conceptual ideas, detailed design, and design rationale both verbally and visually
- Develop diagrams, wireframes, visual mockups, click-through, and prototypes.
- Develop and maintain a Design System for all platforms and help the team to work more efficiently and consistently.

Product Design Manager at Truck Lagbe Limited From MAY 2021 to MAY 2022.

Truck Lagbe is the largest and pioneer in truck & pickup rental service provider.

- I'm leading the most talented team of 5+ designers and design functional and useable products for the current 2M+ & future billion users through mobile, web, B2B apps.
- I'm working collaboratively with cross-functional teams including Tech, Business, Marketing, and other groups.
- Conceive, plan and drive the development of high-end, useful digital products.
- · Facilitated the design team in developing and maintaining the design system, implementing the design process to increase team productivity by around 25%.
- Designed and evaluated a centralized Design System. Maintained consistency and continuity, saveing around 25% of designers' and developers' productive time.

Sr. Product Designer at ShareTrip Inc. From SEP 2018 to APR 2021.

ShareTrip is the country's first and pioneer online travel aggregator (OTA).

- I have designed functional and delightful experience through mobile, web, B2C & B2B apps. for 1.2M+ & future billion users.
- Assembled informative insights from research and interviews. Made strategic decisions using rapidly testing and design thinking approach, improved usability by about 54%
- Collaborated & co-ordinated with CEO, engineers, and other stakeholders to define UX problems and improve user engagement and generated about 56% growth in active
- Created seamless and intuitive booking experience through the platform with about 86% success rate.

UX Consultant (part-time) at JoBike From JAN 2019 to From JUN 2019.

Jobike is an on-demand bicycle-sharing service. Worked on 3+ web & mobile apps.

- Redesign & automate the support system and also enhance the bicycle battery efficiency by 30%.
- Designed a more improved & secured user account recharge process, which helps to get positive user reviews.

- +880 175 969 3045
- anamoulrouf.bd@gmail.com
- anamoulrouf.com
- anamoulrouf.com/portfolio
- in linkedin.com/in/roufuxdesigner

Education

Google UX

Google Career Certificates (Coursera) 2020 - 21

Design Thinking for Innovation

Darden School of Business (Coursera) 2020 - 21

Conducting Usability Testing

IDF 2020 - 21

Human-Centered Design

UCSan Diego (Coursera) 2019 - 20

Gamification

University of Pennsylvania (Coursera) 2020 - 21

BBS, Business Studies

National University, Bangladesh 2005 - 09

+ More

Skills

User Interview

• User Research

• Competitor Analysis • Rapid Prototyping

 Contextual Inquiry Persona

Scenario

 Storyboarding Information Architects

 Sketches Wireframing

Heuristic Evaluation

· Usability Testing

· Think Alouds

· Visual Design

· Responsive Design

 Design System Design

Documentation Design Handover

Iteration

Problem Solving

Interaction Design

+ More

Tools

Figma

Adobe XD

FigJam

· Adobe Creative Suit

 Balsamiq Miro

 Zeplin Notion

+ More

Work Interest

- Augmented Reality (AR) Virtual Reality (VR)
- · Design for Al-Driven Tech
- Problem Solving by Product Design
- · User Survey Data Analysis.